m -90 -22 l -90 26 l 90 26 l 90 -22
DC官方中字
双语制作 薛定谔的加菲猫
伊拉塔维鲁星的人们
Citizens of Planet Earatavikslu,
为便于保存 你们的星球已被扫描
your world has been scanned and compressed into a smaller file
并被压缩为一个较小的文件
for efficient storage and preservation.
不必客气
You are welcome.
银河中最大的行星数据库 又离完成更近了一步
The largest planet database in the galaxy is one planet closer to completion.
D到E的架子总算要放满了
Finally, every spot on the D through E shelf will now be full.
伊拉塔维鲁星现在完蛋了
Planet Earatavikslu is now damaged.
我的收藏只能吸收状态完好的行星
My collection can only assimilate planets in mint condition.
重新计算 重新计算 重新计算
Recalculating, recalculating, recalculating.
恢复电路平衡
Circuit balance restored.
眼下 我得算出一个D或E开头的可替代的行星
Now, I must calculate an alternative world that will go between Buzizz and Eberth.
要是有个行星是E–A开头的就好了
If only there was another planet that started with E-A.
检索中
Searching...
找到所需资料文件
Required data file located.
达克赛德说在我的数码建议箱中 符合条件的星球就是
The very planet that Darkseid told me about in my digital suggestions box,
地球
the planet Earth.
重新计算
Recalculating...
乐高DC超级英雄：正义联盟之宇宙冲击
当火星追猎者 绿箭侠和蝙蝠侠联手
When Martian Manhunter, Green Arrow and Batman team up,
猎豹女和原始人之流的罪犯不堪一击
criminals like Cheetah and Vandal Savage don't stand a chance.
现在要去见正义联盟的其他成员
And now to meet up with the rest of the league, the Justice League.
真奇怪 去年我还在犹豫要不要加入
Strange to think that only last year, I was hesitant to join them,
现在却觉得能成为有史以来最具奉献 最勇敢
and now I could not be more proud to be a member of most dedicated, intrepid
最专业的英雄团体中的一员而无比自豪
and professional band of heroes, history has ever known.
让我们来看看他们在忙些什么
Let's see what they are up to.
92 93 94
92, 93, 94...
95 96 97 98
95, 96, 97, 98...
闪电侠 我能听出来你还没躲好
Flash, I can still hear you trying to find a hiding spot.
最好快点
Better hurry!
- 99 - 不行
- 99... - No.
100!
准备好没 我来啦
Ready or not, here I come!
绿灯侠藏在椅子后面
And Green Lantern is behind the armchair.
嘿 不公平 说好了不许用超能力的
Hey, no fair! I thought we said that you couldn't use your superpowers.
你用了X射线视觉
X-ray vision much?
没有 那是正义大堂里唯一一个绿色的家具
I didn't. It was the only piece of green furniture in the Hall of Justice.
你说得对
Oh. Right!
钢骨在神奇女侠的隐形飞机里
Cyborg is in Wonder Woman's invisible jet.
天 他怎么做到的
Dang! How does he do it?
钢骨啊 我总是跟你说
Golly, Cyborg. I keep telling you,
神奇女侠的飞机是隐形的 可是里面的人是看得见的
Wonder Woman's plane is invisible except for the person in it.
真的 那这飞机有什么用
Really? Why would that be helpful in any way?
维克
Vic!
找到神奇女侠了
I found Wonder Woman!
对不起 神奇女侠
I'm sorry, Wonder Woman.
你现身了 输了游戏
You gave up your hiding space and lost a game
都是为了阻止我做蠢事
just to keep me from doing something dumb!
我知道你有多想赢
And I know how competitive you are.
别担心 钢骨
Think nothing of it, Cyborg.
在天堂岛
On Paradise Island,
我们亚马逊人觉得善待他人是最重要的
we Amazons learn that the wellbeing of others is always what matters most.
她人太好了
She is so nice.
你不可能找到我
You couldn't find me!
我藏在一个绝妙的地方
I hid in the perfect place.
纽约
New York?
他怎么做到的
How does he do it?
超人 你真是玩捉迷藏的个中好手
Superman, you really are the best at hide-and-go-seek.
你能找到所有人
You can find anybody.
嘻嘻 谢谢
Oh, gee. Thanks.
我小时候当童子军的时候 他们总说要时刻准备着
You know when I was in the Scouts as a kid, they always told me to be prepared.
嘿 蝙蝠侠
Hey, Batman!
我们刚在练习各自伪装的技巧 而且…
We were just, um, honing our skills of camouflage and, and, and...
要像你一样做到悄无声息
Being stealthy, you now, like you!
你们不按计划去履行职责
Instead of performing your scheduled duties
维护世界的正义 却在玩捉迷藏
and monitoring the world for injustice, you were playing hide-and-go-seek.
超人在2分钟内就把你们都找出来了
Superman was "it" and found each of you within two minutes.
他真是世上最猛的侦探
He really is the world's greatest detective.
布鲁斯 玩游戏没叫你 对不起 我们可以…
Gee whiz, Bruce, I'm sorry we didn't invite you to play. We could...
穿着这身衣服的时候 不要提秘密的身份
Secret identities are not to be mentioned while in costume.
《正义联盟行为规范》第一页上写着呢
As stated in the Justice League Rule Book, page one.
蝙蝠侠 你似乎不喜欢我们这个友好的运动
Our friendly exercise didn't seem like the kind of thing you'd enjoy, Batman,
不像打击犯罪那么喜欢
not like, uh, fighting crime.
友好的运动 我完全理解
Friendly exercise. I understand completely.
我阴暗和神秘的本性会吓到罪犯
My dark and mysterious nature terrifies criminals,
威胁到我的敌人 也能阻碍友谊
intimidates my enemies, and discourages friendships.
我明白
I'm okay with that.
什么 别犯傻了
What? Don't be silly.
你当然是我们的朋友
Of course you're our friend.
我们都是朋友 我们是超棒的朋友
We're all friends. We're like super friends.
超级棒的朋友
Super best friends!
朱庇特和兄弟波塞冬、哈得斯三分天下
- 就像朱庇特和波塞冬一样 - 兄弟们 咱是朋友
- Like Jupiter and Poseidon. - Buddies, amigos.
老实说啊
Uh, let's be honest,
这家伙最喜欢的消遣 就是想方设法打倒我们每个人
this is the guy whose favorite pastime is dreaming up ways to defeat each of us,
以防我们突然成为恶魔
should we suddenly turn evil.
我打赌他屁股口袋里装着氪星石
I bet he is carrying kryptonite in his back pocket right now.
我裤子后面没有口袋
I don't have back pockets.
你对这里的伙伴们没有信心
And you sure don't have faith in your colleagues here either.
很难把这样的人当做朋友
It's hard to call a guy like that a friend.
我想蝙蝠侠不是那种"我们出去好好玩"类型的朋友
Well, I suppose Batman's not so much of a "Let's hang out and goof off," friend.
他更像是"好好把事做完"那种朋友
He's more of a "Let's get things done" friend.
- 对 - 没错
- Right. - Exactly!
要是我们做很要紧的事
Like, if we were doing something important,
比如打击犯罪或者粉刷神奇女侠的公寓 我们一定会叫上你
like fighting crime or painting Wonder Woman's apartment, we'd totally call you.
没有解释的必要
No need to explain.
我不需要朋友 黑暗骑士踽踽独行
I don't need friends the Dark Knight walks alone.
蝙蝠侠
Batman...
钢骨的移动麻烦警报响了
Cyborg's mobile trouble alert.
威胁似乎是来自外太空的
The threat appears to be space-based.
把联盟的卫星调到德尔塔27 横坐标5
Readjust the League's satellite to coordinates delta 27, grid five.
遵命
On it.
在那 有什么东西
There it is. I see something.
提高分辨率
Increasing resolution.
哦 不
Oh, no.
你知道那是什么吗
You know what that is?
知道 我们必须得在它抵达地球前阻止它
Yes, I do. And we have to stop it before it reaches Earth.
上飞船
To the Javelin.
正义大堂
准备起飞 各位系好安全带
Prepare for launch. Everyone, buckle in.
谁会用安全带啊 我飞得比这飞船还快
Ah, who needs a seat belt? I can run faster than this bucket.
三 二 一 起飞
Three, two, one, blast off.
在任何情况下都要系安全带 无一例外
Everyone, everyone needs to buckle up, every time.
好吧 我懂你的意思了
Okay, I see your point.
超人 你说你知道那是什么
Superman, you said you know what this thing is?
很不幸
Unfortunately.
那是一个叫脑怪的有感知能力的机器人的飞船
That ship belongs to a sentient robot named Brainiac.
更像一个叫什么怪的傻瓜 对吗
More like dumb-name-iac! Am I right?
我跟你击掌 可我并不认同你的说法
I'm high-fiving you for that, but my heart isn't in it.
电脑 从超人的飞船连接氪星的数据库
Computer, access Kryptonian database from Superman Baby rocket.
就是那架把孩提的你从受难的星球送来地球的飞船
That's the alien rocket that brought you to Earth as an infant from a doomed planet.
没错 我知道
Yes, I know.
脑怪是以终极人工智能为目的设计的
Brainiac was designed to be the ultimate artificial intelligence.
目的是为后代把现有的宇宙进行分类
Built to catalog the existing universe for future generations.
悲剧的是 一场意外导致程序出现差错
Unfortunately, due to an accident and a glitch in his programing,
它现在在银河系中搜寻星球进行捕获
Brainiac now scours the galaxy looking for planets to capture,
并将其永久保存在其不断增长的收藏中
and permanently preserve in his growing collection.
完全明白
Oh, I totally get the impulse.
我收藏纪念版的咖啡杯
I collect commemorative coffee mugs.
这个是尼亚加拉大瀑布的 这个是大峡谷的
This one is from Niagara Falls, this one is from the Grand Canyon,
这个是从生产咖啡杯的工厂买来的纪念品
this one is a souvenir coffee mug from a factory that makes coffee mugs.
拜托你住口吧
Please stop.
我回地球 不是为了听闪电侠说咖啡杯的
I did not come back to Earth to listen to Flash talk about coffee mugs!
脑怪要如何把整个星球抓起来呢
How can Brainiac capture entire civilizations?
四个字 缩小光线
Two words. Shrink ray.
实际上 那是一个词 不过我不会计较这个
Actually, shrink-ray is a single hyphenated word, but I'll let that pass.
缩小光线
Shrink-ray.
省地方的好办法
That would be a great way to save storage space!
用不着的时候 可以缩小圣诞装饰物
You could just shrink your Christmas decorations when you didn't need...
好了 各位 这是个头号威胁 我希望你们…
All right, team, this is a class one threat so I want you to...
好了 不必说了
All right, enough talk...
我才不怕这个成长过度的自大的计算机
I'm not afraid of this overgrown calculator with attitude.
绿灯侠 我们都知道你无所畏惧 不过请等到…
Lantern, we all know you are fearless. Just wait until...
至少我可以给其他人制定计划…
At least I can make a plan for the rest...
就是那种感觉
So, that's what that feels like.
往后2毫米
Two millimeters backward.
就这样
Ah, there!
所有的瓶子又一样齐了
Now, all the jars are once again even.
完美
Perfect!
这是什么
What's this?
地球的资料显示有防火墙
The Earth data file appears to have a firewall defense.
启动恶意程序
Activating malware.
请报上姓名
Please identify yourselves by name.
我要按名字先后把你们干掉
I prefer to defeat you in alphabetical order.
正义联盟是不会被归档 盖戳  索引 分类或收藏的
The Justice League will not be filed, stamped, indexed, cataloged, or collected.
那你就会被删除
Then, you will be deleted.
控制 换挡 消灭
Control, alt, destroy.
导弹 你要是以为几发这玩意我就会害怕…
Missiles! If you think I'm gonna turn chicken because of a bunch of...
有火光激光束的导弹
Missiles that fire laser beams?
不 还是不怕
Nope, still not afraid.
还好我把手镯都擦亮了
Glad I polished these bracelets.
进入
Incoming!
看我的旋转激光攻击
Check out my spinning laser attack!
那看我的"小心这些导弹"攻击
Oh, yeah? Well, check out my, taking-care-of-these-missiles attack.
名字我还没想好
I'm still working on the name.
继续想吧 闪电侠
You keep working on that, Flash.
与此同时 我来告诉你该怎么啃这些炸弹
In the meantime, I'll show you how to put the bite on these bombs.
看见没
See what I did there?
男孩总是争来争去的
Ugh, boys. Always fighting.
也许我们可以平静地解决问题
Perhaps we can solve this peacefully.
嘿
Hey!
好吧 你自找的 兄弟
Okay, you asked for it, buddy.
你赏了他一个黑眼圈
You gave him a black eye!
也许应该穿上喷射推进器
Probably, should have slipped into that jetpack.
别急 闪电侠 我送你回去战斗
Don't worry, Flash. I'll get you back in the fight.
哦 不
Oh, no.
神奇女侠 看那个胡子
Wonder Woman, check out the mustache.
闪电侠 你啊 真上进
Flash! Look at you. You are quite the go-getter.
别忘了 我磁化了你的宇宙靴
And don't forget, I magnetized your space boots.
我的靴子和我本人一样具有吸引力了
Hey, hey, now my boots will match my magnetic personality.
脑怪 看这个
Hey, Brainiac, get a load of this.
这下你的头真的会转过来了
Here's something that will really turn your head.
轻而易举
Too easy.
毁掉自己的飞船不在程序之内
Destroying my peripherals is not part of the program.
错误 错误
Error, error!
重新计算
Recalculating.
地球人
Units of Earth...
你们的星球被我选中 要做我档案中永久的备份
I have selected your planet for permanent back-up in my archives.
等着变小吧
Prepare to be downsized.
启动缩小光线
Activating shrink-ray.
各位后退 我来
Everyone, stand back, I've got this.
我的缩小光线 你毁了它
My shrink-ray! You broke it!
吸收太阳光能让我精神焕发
Nothing like soaking up some rays from old Mr. Sunshine to charge up my powers.
地球不想也不需要你那个储存的方法
The Earth doesn't want or need your type of saving.
它有正义联盟守护
It is under the protection of the Justice League.
访问正义联盟
Accessing Justice League.
超级速度 超级回路 超级战士 超级宝石
Super speed, super circuits, super warrior, super jewelry.
这家伙没超能力
And this one has no powers?
他不在话下
Well, he won't be a problem.
超级外星人
Super alien?
氪星人你好啊 你不该是这个星球的人
Ah, greetings Kryptonian, you are mis-assigned to an incorrect planet.
要把你重新分类
You will be re-cataloged.
话别说太满
Don't count on it.
他已经罪有应得了 超人
I think he's had enough, Superman.
你不是真要伤他吧
You don't wanna really hurt him.
当然不会
No, of course not.
重新计算
Recalculating, recalculating...
这样就行了
Well, that should do it.
有时候我会忘记 我吸收了太阳很多能量这事
Sometimes I forget how much power I absorb from the Sun.
脑怪已经恢复控制了 不过撤退了
Brainiac has regained control, but is retreating.
很好
Yes!
- 很好 - 太好了 漂亮
- All right! Yes! - All right! Great job! Yeah!
拜拜 没用的什么怪 不然叫你逃跑怪
Bye-bye, Lame-iac, or should I call you Run-away-niac?
我不想毁气氛 可是氧气不多
I hate to break up the party, but we only have so much oxygen
而闪电侠每次说话都在消耗它
and Flash tends to burn through it every time he starts talking!
不是每次啦
Hmm, not every time.
看来我好像
It seems that I...
低估了正义联盟的水准
Miscalculated the power level of the Justice League units.
最大程度上进行计算 有92%的可能性
Calculating to the nth degree, there is a 92% probability
正义联盟会妨碍我得到地球
of this Justice League preventing my acquisition of planet Earth.
修正计划
Amending plan...
回到脑怪基地对飞船进行修复和升级
Return to Brainiac Prime for required repair and upgrade.
脑怪1.1 我探知你回来了
Brainiac 1.1. I ascertain that you are back.
当然 1.4
Clearly, 1.4...
在和一群有超能力的人的较量中 我的飞船遭到了破坏
My vessel sustained damage in an altercation with super-powered beings.
务必修好它
See that she is repaired!
可以再上一层蜡
And it could do with a coat of wax.
明白 脑怪1.1 会修好的
Understood, Brainiac 1.1. It will be done.
脑怪1.4 收到
Acknowledged, Brainiac 1.4.
脑怪
And, Brainiac?
什么事 脑怪
Yes, Brainiac?
上两层
Two coats.
不要像上次一样糊弄了事
Don't skimp like last time.
"不要像上次一样糊弄了事"
"Don't skimp like last time."
这不是最强的脑怪1.1吗
Well, if isn't the mighty Brainiac 1.1?
脑怪1.2 脑怪1.3 幸会
Brainiac 1.2, Brainiac 1.3, nice to see you!
你的飞船上多了个胡子 被升级了啊
It appears your vessel has been upgraded with a mustache.
又多了个黑眼圈被降级了
And downgraded with a black eye!
连缩小光线都不起作用
Even the shrink-ray is inoperative.
没什么是我解决不了的
Nothing that I can't handle!
然后 我要用
However, I shall require
配件一应俱齐的脑怪高级飞船
the premium Brainiac vessel with all the extras.
虽然它没有缩小光线 可高级飞船是无可比拟的
Although, it lacks a shrink-ray, the premium vessel is exceptional!
为什么你能用高级飞船
How come you get to use the premium vessel?
因为 脑怪1.3 脑怪1.2
Because, Brainiac 1.3, 1.2,
我是脑怪1.1
I am Brainiac 1.1!
我要回到地球 开始进行分类工作
I will return to Earth and begin the cataloging process.
我的船一修好 你们就给我送过来
You will deliver my original vehicle to me as soon as it is repaired.
你现在是第一 可是很快我就是第一了
You're number one for now, but soon, I'll be number one.
你现在是第二 可是很快我就是第二了
You're number two for now, but soon, I'll be number two.
那个脑怪就是渣渣
That Brainiac is a jerk.
看到超人是怎么把那玩意扔出去的没
Did you see the way Superman threw that thing?
快速的旋转
Put some serious spin on it.
他都能去职棒比赛投球了
My boy could pitch for the Majors!
可我才不会去呢 那太不公平了
But I would never do that because it wouldn't be fair.
话说回来 没有好朋友的帮忙 我也孤掌难鸣
Anyway, I couldn't have done it without the help of my closest friends.
还有同事的帮忙
Oh, and also my work colleagues.
不用介意蝙蝠侠 超人
Don't mind Bat, Superman.
他也许在想什么新鬼点子 好用氪星石消灭你
He's probably thinking up sneaky new ways to destroy you with Kryptonite
或者怎么在战争中干掉我们
or defeat the rest of us in battle.
尽管我们这个礼拜 第一百万次地拯救了地球
Even though we just saved the planet for, like, the millionth time this week.
实际上 绿灯侠
Actually, Green Lantern,
我在想脑怪撤退的路线
I was thinking that we need to figure out the trajectory of Brainiac's retreat.
最好做好他杀回来的准备
Best to be prepared when he decides to make a return visit.
回来 被打成那德行之后还回来
Return? After a spanking like that?
我打赌这辈子都不会再见到那怪胎了
Yeah, I'm bettin' we'll never see that freak again.
麻烦警报
也许他只是路过
Maybe he's just passing by.
他的新飞船又小又萌的
His new ride is so tiny and cute.
没问题 我来搞定它
Not a problem, I'll deal with it.
不管上次我们多速战速决 脑怪还是个强大的敌人
Despite our quick victory last time, Brainiac is a formidable foe.
我觉得我们该制定一个战术
I think we should come up with a game plan.
行
Yeah, okay.
绿灯侠 你也来吗
Um, Green Lantern, do you wanna come too?
我不怕那个单调的节拍器
I'm not afraid of that monotone metronome.
跟你之前说的一样
As you've said before.
- 神奇女侠呢  - 当然去
- Wonder Woman? - Absolutely!
也许交战前我就可以控制住局势
Perhaps, I can diffuse the situation before a confrontation arises,
先用亚马逊人的方式
the preferred Amazon way.
不行的话 就用拳头
And if not, it's beat down time.
我想的是更有深度的战术
Hmm, I was thinking a more in-depth plan.
这挺好的
Oh, this is gonna be good!
我打赌超人会让这家伙
I bet Superman is really going to make this guy
后悔回到我们的领土的
regret coming back to our neck of the woods.
不许再靠近了 脑怪
That's far enough, Brainiac.
正义联盟超能力最强的三个家伙
Ah, the three most powerful units of the Justice League.
真意外啊
How fortuitous!
我的计算表明为了获得地球
My calculations indicated that you are the exact units I need
你们是我必须消灭的人
to eliminate in order to acquire planet Earth.
暂时异常
那个能量记号 暂时异常
That energy signature... A temporal anomaly.
超人 神奇女侠 绿灯侠 快跑
Superman, Wonder Woman, Green Lantern, get out of there!
马上投降 脑怪
Surrender immediately, Brainiac.
我们已经跟你浪费太多时间了
We've already wasted enough time fighting with you.
你要去哪啊 神奇女侠
Where you're going, Wonder Woman,
现在你有充足的时间了
you will now have all the time in the world.
他们没了
They're gone!
脑怪消灭了超人 神奇女侠和绿灯侠
Brainiac destroyed Superman, and Wonder Woman, and Green Lantern.
不 我不敢相信 脑怪赢了
No, no, no, no, I can't believe it. Brainiac won?
超人 神奇女侠 绿灯侠
Oh, Superman, Wonder Woman, Green Lantern,
也许你们不在了 但你们将流芳千古
you may be gone forever, but you'll never be forgotten.
他们没死 闪电侠
They're not dead, Flash.
只是消失了
They're simply lost in time.
他们什么
They're what?
正义大堂的传感器在脑怪发出射线前
The Hall of Justice sensors picked up a temporal anomaly
捕获到异常
just before Brainiac's ray fired off.
如果如我所料
If I'm right...
他什么时候错过
And when is he not?
脑怪知道他的火力斗不过联盟
Brainiac knows he doesn't have the firepower to destroy the League.
可是他能把它们送回到过去
But he can... Send them back through time?
我可以追踪残留的气息
I can trace the residual temporal currents,
调整设备 他们被放下的话 我就能精确找到…
and calibrate a device that can pinpoint when in time they've been placed...
他们在那
And, there they are.
蝙蝠侠 我们要做的是不是和我想的一样
Batman, does this mean that we're gonna build what I think we're gonna build?
理论上是没错 可我们得试试
It's only been a theory, but we have to try.
试什么
Try what?
闪电侠 你能快速带我们去蝙蝠洞吗
Flash, can you get us to the Batcave quickly?
没问题 快就是我的绰号
No problem. Fast is my middle name!
- 是吗  - 不是
- It is? - No.
给 抓紧绳子 等等
Here, tow ropes. Hold on!
钢骨 自己把自己组装好
Pull yourself together, Cyborg.
哇 蝙蝠洞
The Batcave!
我们应该来这玩 可以玩空中曲棍球 看电影还有…
We should totally hang out here. We could play air hockey and watch movies and...
当然是在我们拯救地球之后
After we save the world, obviously.
花了四分钟
Ugh, four minutes!
对不起 时间长了点
Sorry it took so long. You know what'd be great,
要是从大都会到哥谭市有个通道就好了 是不
if there was a tunnel all the way from Metropolis to Gotham, right?
对 我会去修的
Yeah, I'll get right on that.
可与其同时 我们也有要忙的
But in the meantime, we've got a job to do.
它真好看
She is beautiful.
它真华丽 真是…
She is gorgeous. She is...
它是什么
What is she?
宇宙跑步机
The Cosmic Treadmill.
是时光机器 通过我的超速度来运转
She's a time machine powered by my super speed.
理论是这样没错
At least in theory.
闪电侠和我设计了这台设备 可还没测试过
Flash and I have been developing the plans for this device but we've never tested it.
启动之后 会在时间流中打开一道裂缝
Once activated, it could very well create a rift in the time stream
在宇宙中引发连锁反应
causing a chain reaction throughout the universe
导致宇宙中的时空本身瓦解
causing all of space-time to collapse in on itself.
这可不太妙
That would not be good.
麻烦警报
Trouble alert.
地球人你们好啊 我是脑怪 有好消息要告诉你们
Greetings Earth units, I am Brainiac and I bring good news.
这条广播是面向全世界的
This is being broadcast all over the world.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
我有内置卫星 无线网和收音机 每个频道都是他
I've got built-in satellite, Wi-Fi, and AM-FM radio, and he's on every channel.
为了给子孙创造精确的记录
Soon I will begin scanning and cataloging every species on this planet,
我很快就要开始 对这个星球上的物种进行扫描和分类
in order to create a precise record for posterity.
这听着还行啊
Well, that doesn't sound so bad.
工作完成后 我会把你们的星球缩小成更有效的文档尺寸
Once finished, I will shrink your planet to a more efficient file size,
放到一个玻璃瓶里
place it inside a glass bottle,
永久性地保管在我的文明社会图书馆中
and store it safely in my library of civilizations for all eternity.
不必客气
You're welcome.
这部分内容我可不喜欢了
Now, that part I'm not so crazy about.
没功夫测试了
No time for a test run.
我们得在脑怪完成星球的索引前
We've got to retrieve Superman, Wonder Woman and Green Lantern
救回超人 神奇女侠和绿灯侠
before Brainiac finishes indexing the planet.
闪电侠 靠你了
Flash, it's all up to you.
在你说过整个宇宙会瓦解之后
Definitely not crazy about this plan either
我也着实不喜欢这个计划
after that whole collapsing universe thingy you mentioned.
那我呢
What about me?
回正义大堂 联系任何能联系上的辅助成员
Return to the Hall of Justice and call in any available auxiliary Leaguers.
看看能不能拖延脑怪索引地球的速度
See if you can slow down Brainiac's indexing process.
- 遵命 - 快点 闪电侠
- On it. - Faster, Flash.
朋友们 祝你们好运
And, guys, good luck.
我不相信运气
I don't believe in luck.
那你相信什么
What do you believe in?
蝙蝠侠
Batman!
闪电侠 开始
Flash, hit it.
再快点 闪电侠 宇宙跑步机正在打开
Faster, Flash. The Cosmic Treadmill is creating a temporal rift
通向神奇女侠所在的史前时期的临时裂缝
at Wonder Woman's pre-historic location.
希望有用
I hope this works!
我们还活着
We're alive!
就算是我也觉得好快啊
Phew. Ah, that was pretty fast, even for me.
真想歇会
I'll be glad to sit down.
别停 闪电侠 你要继续跑
Stay put! Flash, you have to keep running.
蝙蝠车留在这个时间段里 需要大量的能量
It takes an enormous amount of energy to keep the Batmobile in this timescape.
你要是停了 宇宙跑步机就会突然回到我们的时代
If you stop, the Cosmic Treadmill will snap back to our own era,
我们这辈子都离不开这里了
trapping us here forever.
好
Okay!
我猜我继续跑就行了
So, I guess I'll just keep running then.
你呢
And, you?
进入一个不同时代的第一法则就是伪装
The first rule of infiltrating a different time era is camouflage.
要找到神奇女侠 我得入乡随俗
I'll need to blend in in order to find out where Wonder Woman is.
入乡随俗
Blend in?
山顶洞蝙蝠装 你在车里放了这个
A Bat caveman outfit? You keep that in your car?
对
Yes.
临时读数显示是在西边
It looks like the temporal reading is west of here.
我去查探下 你继续跑
I'll go scout it out. You keep running.
好 我会待在跑步机上
Okay, I'll just be here on the Treadmill.
需要我的话 我就跑
Running, if you need me.
你跟俺来
You come with me now.
放了啊哈 你个畜生
Let Ugh go, you beast.
汪达尔萨维奇
Vandal Savage.
正义联盟永远的敌人 回到了他出生的时代
The Justice League's never-aging nemesis back in the time he came from.
看上去他天生就不是善类
Looks like he's been up to no good since the beginning of history.
安静 啊哈
Quiet, Arg!
叫也救不了你
Your grunting not save you.
俺叫啊哈 女皇会找到俺的
My name, Ugh! And Queen am going to find me.
你是俺的人质 等俺找到俺能统治的新国家
Well, you am my hostage, and when we find new country that me can rule,
你就是俺欺压的第一个子民
you will be first citizen me oppress.
话别说太满 萨维奇
Don't count on it, Savage.
只有未开化的畜生才会威胁一个女人或者别人
Only an uncivilized brute threatens a woman, or anyone else for that matter.
俺不知道为什么你知道俺的名字
I not know how you know my name.
可你干嘛穿得像只老鼠
But why you dressed like a rat?
是蝙蝠
It's a bat.
你把神奇女侠怎么了
And what have you done with Wonder Woman?
俺不懂你在鬼扯什么
Me no understand your crazy talk.
另外 俺也没时间跟你废话
Plus, me have no time to chew mastodon fat with you!
那就抽出时间
Make time.
你自找的 老鼠皮
You am asked for this, Rat Skins.
你这二货
Men, you am so dumb.
趁你们打架 啊哈抓住了你们
While you fight, Ugh catches you.
啊哈 你在干嘛
Ugh, what are you doing?
俺们要把你们带到山顶洞女皇跟前
We take you to Cave Queen now.
俺们
We?
对
Yeah.
所以我跟他说
So I tell him,
红砖没前途 要投资黄砖
there's no future in red bricks, you should invest in yellow bricks!
太棒了
Excellent.
干掉了正义联盟的三个人之后
With three members of the Justice League out of the way,
地球很快就会有个新家了
the Earth will soon have a new home...
就在我的收藏品D到E里
In my collection right between Dzizz and Eberth.
登录名 钢骨 密码 Batfan1
Login name, Cyborg. Password, Batfan1.
正义联盟之书
海王的状态是
Aquaman, status?
"海下2万名成员"
"20,000 leagues under the sea."
去不了那
So, no go there.
到了脱毛的季节 鹰侠回沙纳加了
Hawkman returned to Thanagar for molting season?
话说这是什么
What is that, anyway?
绿箭侠在兰恩星开了弓箭课
Green Arrow is giving an archery clinic on Rann?
那个星球上的所有人都配有射线枪
Everyone on that planet has a ray gun!
超人的秘密武器
Superman's secret weapon.
非常之时行非常之法
Desperate times call for super measures.
喂
Hello?
什么
What?
真的吗 联盟需要我
Really? The League needs me?
你签了我的家长同意书
And you signed my permission slip?
我一定不负所托 钢骨
Well, I won't let you down, Cyborg.
抱歉 姑娘们 我得走了
Sorry, girls, got to run!
有急事
Emergency!
我真想马上让正义联盟的人看看 超女也是个好伙伴
Ooh, I can't wait to show the Justice League that Supergirl is a team player.
这些石头有种奇怪的熟悉感
These rocks are strangely familiar.
我在史前的蝙蝠洞
I am in the pre-historic Batcave!
俺不知道你在哪
Me not know who you are,
但要不是因为你 俺就能躲过她寻仇了
but if not for you, me would have escaped her vengeance!
现在被关在这个又是石头又热的地方
Now we stuck between rock and hot place.
她寻仇
Her vengeance?
她是谁
Who is this her?
她是必须服从的人
She who must be obeyed!
你很快就能亲眼见到了
You am soon see for self.
还会发抖
And tremble!
女皇 女皇 女皇
Queen, queen, queen, queen, queen, queen, queen...
不好 她来了
Oh, no! She comes!
谁来了
Who comes?
神奇女侠
Wonder Woman!
安静 恶棍
Silence, miscreant male.
你被抓是因为帮汪达尔萨维奇 从我手下人手中逃跑
You've been caught helping the evil Vandal Savage escape with one of my women.
所以 你要像烤鹅一样被山中之火洗礼
And for that, you will be cleansed in the fire of the mountain like roasted geese.
显然 脑怪的时间光束震动太大
Hmm, apparently, Brainiac's time-beam
造成了某种记忆缺失
is so jarring it creates a form of amnesia.
如果我能让她恢复记忆
If I can get her to remember who she is,
时间流本身的弹性就会推开她
the timestream's natural elasticity should reject her,
把她送回我们的时代
sending her back to our own time.
可现在该怎么办
But, how?
把他们当猪一样慢慢往下放到火里
Lower them into the fire like the pigs they are!
知道名字已经不重要了 俺们难逃一劫了
No point in learning name now. We am doomed!
神奇女侠 等等
Wonder Woman, wait!
什么男人胆敢和俺们女皇讲话
What male dares speak to our queen?
你说吧
You may speak.
你不记得我了 可我是来带你回家的
You don't remember me, but I have come to bring you home.
回家
Home?
除了这儿我没有别的家
I know no home but here.
女皇来的时候 俺们在受汪达尔萨维奇的山顶洞人欺压
When queen arrived, we subjugated by Vandal Savage's cavemen.
她向你们压迫者光荣起义
She led glorious revolt against you oppressors.
我跟他们不是一伙的
I am not one of them.
想想 神奇女侠 你认识我
Think, Wonder Woman, you know me.
我是你的 是你的
I'm your... I'm your...
同事
Co-worker.
我是蝙蝠侠
I'm Batman.
蝙蝠侠
Batman?
你觉得伟大的女皇 会和一个男人结盟吗
You think great Queen would ally herself with a man?
也许你不了解我 可我了解你
You may not know me, but I know you.
我蝙蝠侠 对这场审判 向山顶洞女人的女皇发出挑战
I, Batman, challenge the Queen of the Cavewomen to ritual trial by combat.
还是说你害怕和一个男人打架
Or do you fear to do battle against a man?
我不怕男人
I fear no man!
战斗 战斗 战斗
Combat, combat, combat, combat, combat, combat...
恐龙
Oh, oh, dinosaurs!
蝙蝠侠 蝙蝠侠 拜托 快点
Batman, oh, Batman, please... Anytime now.
我会速战速决的
I will make this quick.
机会只有一次 时机必须拿捏得当
I only have one chance at this. My timing must be perfect.
没有绳子能捆住我 男人
No rope can hold me, man!
我不需要用你的魔法套锁来捆住你
I don't need your magic lasso to hold you.
我要用它让你跟我说实话
I need it to make you tell me the truth.
你是谁
Who are you?
我…我是女皇
I... I... I am Queen of...
魔法套锁会逼你说真话
The magic lasso compels you to speak the truth,
就算是你忘了的事
even a truth you've forgotten.
我…我…
I... I...
我是神奇女侠
I am Wonder Woman!
我的史前珀尔塞福涅啊
Pre-historic Persephone!
蝙蝠侠 你救了我 可现在怎么办
Batman, you rescued me, but how?
没时间解释了 如果如我所料…
No time to explain, if I am right...
你总是对的
You usually are.
现在你记起你是谁了 时间流会试着自动修正
Now that you've remembered who you are, the timestream will try to correct itself
你会被传回我们的时代
and you will transition back to our time.
已经开始了
It's happening already.
闪电侠和我去找其他人
Flash and I will get the others.
你去确保脑怪不会缩小地球
You make sure that Brainiac doesn't shrink the Earth.
啊哈 我最忠诚的仆人 现在由你来负责部落
Ugh, my faithful servant, you are left in charge of the clan now.
俺们该怎么处理汪达尔萨维奇
And what we do with Vandal Savage?
那不重要 躲开像他这样的恶魔
No matter. Steer clear of evil men such as him,
谨记 团结力量大
and remember that you are more powerful together than alone.
现在呢
What now?
女皇不在了 俺们没有后盾了
Without Queen, we defenseless.
不
No!
女皇说得没错
What Queen said was true.
团结一致 俺们离开这 去找一方土地
We stick together, we leave this land, find a place!
也许是个岛
An island maybe,
俺们在那过着宁静的生活 远离恶魔
where we live in peace, away from evil of man.
会是个天堂
It would be paradise.
那么就是这样
So, that's how it happened.
得回去找闪电侠 他可能已经无聊疯了
Better get back to Flash. He must be bored out of his mind by now.
蝙蝠侠
Batman!
还看 怎么不拍张照啊
Staring? Why don't you take a picture?
能让你一直看
It'll last longer!
要说对这些行星无人机有什么不能忍的 那就是太无礼了
If there's one thing I cannot abide in interplanetary drones, it's rudeness.
漂亮 超女
Good job, Supergirl.
可打它们来的地方还有更多的无人机 保持警惕
But there's more where that came from. Stay focused.
警惕 它们对我就没那么警惕 钢骨
Focused? Oh, they don't come much more focused than me, Cyborg.
看啊 小猫
Oh, look, a kitten.
耶 钢骨
Yay, Cyborg!
我们很帅 看得出来
We're awesome and it shows.
扫描飞机 被打散开
We're smashing scanner drones.
正义联盟登台 跟脑怪说拜拜
When Justice League is on the case, Brainiac's a loser face.
耶
Yay!
说拜拜
Loser face?
这不可能
That does not even compute.
住手 你们在阻碍…
Stop, you are interfering with the...
这些无人机可不便宜
Those drones are not cheap to build.
我的东西 不许碰我的东西
My stuff! Stop touching my stuff!
重新计算 重新计算 重新计算
Recalculating, recalculating, recalculating...
启动防御计划
Initiating drone defense protocol.
因为这一下 我要为你们的末日助威了
For that you get my cheer of doom.
来个D 来个O 再来个O
Give me a D. Give me an O. Give me another O.
来个M 拼出来是什么
Give me a M... What's that spell?
末日
Doom!
干得好 超女
Woo-hoo. Nice job, Supergirl.
我还纳闷你什么时候才能现身呢
Hey, I was wondering when you'd show up.
神奇女侠 我一直想
Wonder Woman! Oh, I've always wanted to fight evil
跟最棒的英雄们一起打击恶魔
alongside the greatest superhero in the...
这套衣服很有意思
That's an interesting outfit choice.
之后聊 超女 现在开打
Talk later, Supergirl. Fight now.
好
Okay!
无人机 无胜算 打得他们满天窜
Robot drones don't stand a chance, we're gonna kick their underpants.
我们上
Go team!
满天窜
Yeah, underpants!
你去了好久啊
Took you long enough.
没时间闲聊了 闪电侠 下一站 1741年
There's no time to chat, Flash. Next stop, 1741.
加把劲
Step on it.
逗呢 加把劲
Was that a joke? Step on it?
有人知道你这么逗吗 蝙蝠侠
Who knew you were so funny, Batman?
行 行
Okay, okay.
我们在水面上 在下沉
We are on the water. We're gonna sink.
蝙蝠浮舟启动了
Bat-pontoons deployed.
放松 闪电侠 蝙蝠车基本上无所不能
Relax, Flash, the Batmobile is prepared for virtually anything.
真的
Oh, really?
有蝙蝠海盗船吗
Does it come with a Bat-pirate costume?
看仔细点 病狗
Keep a sharp eye, ye scurvy dogs.
雾像恶魔的头屑一样浓
Fog's as thick as the devil's dandruff.
水兵 别动
Avast there, swabby.
甲板要像托尔图加的棚屋
This deck be looking like a Tortuga shanty.
还记得我跟你说过的话吗
Remember what I told ye.
记得 恐惧船长
Aye, aye, Captain Fear, sir.
你说如果你不能在甲板上吃到鳕鱼沙拉
You said that if you couldn't eat your cod salad off the deck of the ship,
就把我扔到大海里去喂鲨鱼
I'd be feeding sharks on the open sea.
那么…
Well...
是 先生 马上 先生
Yes, sir. Okay, sir. Right away, sir.
这才像样
Ah, well, that be more like it.
船长 船左边有东西快速地朝我们开来
Captain, something coming at us fast, off the port side!
是条船
It be a boat.
是条鱼
It be a fish.
不 是个人在鲨鱼背上冲浪
No, it's a dude surfing on a shark.
朋友 你从陆地上远道而来
Well, you be a long way from land there, matey.
我的
I, uh,
船被饥饿的海妖吞了
lost me ship to a hungry kraken,
不得不占用了途经的海洋动物来旅行
and had to commandeer that passing sea critter for travel.
你叫什么
What be your name?
有很多人叫我蝙蝠胡子
There be those would call me Bat Beard.
我没看到胡子
I see no beard.
刮了
I shaved.
我的船上欢迎所有
Well, any man that can tame a great white
像你一样勇敢的能驯服白鲨的人
as fearlessly as ye is welcome on me vessel.
努力工作 和我们一起战斗 就能分享战利品
Work hard and fight alongside us, and you will get part of the plunder.
你怎么看
What say you?
我说好哇
I say huzzah.
好哇
Huzzah!
你这个胆小鬼需要听我的吩咐
Now, you yellow-bellied swabby below my contempt,
带他去看看吊床
show him to his hammock,
之后回前甲板汇报 打扫卫生
then report back to the forecastle, throw dirt on it, and clean it all over again.
遵命 船长
Aye-aye, Captain.
跟我走 陌生人
Follow me, stranger.
宝箱
Treasure chest.
离我的宝藏远点 你这只咸狗
Away from my booty, you salty dog.
兄弟
Huh, dude.
哈尔 是我 蝙蝠侠
Hal, it's me, Batman.
谁 我以为你叫蝙蝠胡子
Who? I thought you said you were Bat Beard.
要是船长知道你在讲谎话 他会…
If the Captain knew you were lying, he'd...
我不知道他会怎么样 可我怕知道结果
Well, I don't know what he'd do, but I'm afraid to find out.
怕
Afraid?
哈尔 你天不怕地不怕
Hal, you aren't afraid of anything.
你的力量戒指呢 在哪
Your power ring, where is it?
那枚绿色的戒指
That green ring?
船长把我从海里钓上来的拿走了 说是给他当船员的酬劳
The Captain took it when he fished me out of the sea as payment to be on his crew.
锁在他的宝箱里
It's locked up in his chest.
我们得拿到它
We have to get it.
那可能是唯一能帮你想起你是谁的办法
It might be the only way to help you remember who you are.
你疯了
Are you mad?
要是船长发现了 他会杀死咱俩的
If the Captain found out, he'd keelhaul us.
没事 我自己去拿
Fine, I'll do it myself.
可得有人帮我分散他的注意
But I need a distraction.
这个最起码你能做吧
Will you at least do that for me?
行
Oh. Uh, okay.
上下 上下 跑啊跑啊…
Up and down, up and down, on and on and...
我感觉不舒服
I don't feel so good.
也许我该吃点东西
Maybe I should eat something.
著名的闪电应急蛋白质
The famous Flash emergency protein. Mmm.
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey!
飞鱼攻击
Flying fish attack!
我真的讨厌跑步机
Oh, I really hate treadmills.
兄弟
Dude.
你这个笨蛋 看看你做的好事
Oh, you clumsy oaf, look what you've done.
你把船弄脏了 你这个差劲的新人
You befouled my ship, you lousy landlubber.
找到什么有趣的东西吗
You find anything interesting?
孩子 海上的第一条规矩
The number one rule of the sea, laddie,
就是别碰船长的宝藏
keep your hands off the captain's booty.
它还有个更好的说法
There's gotta be a better way to phrase that.
你出卖了我 哈尔
You ratted me out, Hal?
对不起 蝙蝠胡子
I'm sorry, Bat Beard.
- 我就是… - 你做得很好 水兵
- I just... - You did good, swabby.
我们这位爱偷东西的朋友
It's time for our sticky-fingered friend here
要去木板上走一走了
to take a little walk... On the plank.
深海阎王戴维·琼斯 幽灵船船长 章鱼脸
也许戴维·琼斯会教会你 不要偷我合法偷来的东西
Maybe Davy Jones will teach you not to steal what I've rightfully stolen.
现在 上木板
Now, out on the plank with ye.
有位老朋友想会会你
There's an old friend waiting to make your acquaintance.
哈尔 也许你不相信
Hal, you may not believe it now,
可我知道你是最勇敢的男人
but I know that you are the most fearless man alive.
成为那个人
Be that man.
别废话了 朋友
Stow your scuttlebutt, matey.
跳进海里
It's into the sea with ye.
我相信你 哈尔
I believe in you, Hal.
有一团蓝火
What in the blue blazes?
错了 恐惧船长 不是蓝色的火 是绿色的
Wrong, Captain Fear, not blue blazes, green.
青天白日 黑夜无边 牛鬼蛇神 难逃法眼
In brightest day, in blackest night, no evil shall escape my sight.
让邪魔的追随者畏我绿灯神光
Let those who worship evil's might, beware my power, Green Lantern's light.
向那个水兵开火 他入魔了
Fire on that swabby, he's bewitched.
我不是你的水兵了 船长
I'm not your swabby anymore, Captain,
我不再听命于恐惧
and I don't take orders from Fear.
怎么回事 不妙 兄弟
What? Not cool, bro.
兄弟
Dude!
吓死老子了 这是恐惧船长最恐惧的一天
Shiver me timbers. Tis the day Captain Fear feared the most.
就因为你说过那些好听的话
Bet you're expecting me to admit I was wrong about you
我打赌你希望我承认我之前看错你了
just because you said all those nice words back there.
我说过我就是想完成工作
I said what I thought might get the job done.
如我所料
I was right.
你什么时候错过
And, when are you not?
蝙蝠侠 我开始要消失了
Batman, I am starting to turn invisible.
那是时间在进行自我修复
That's time repairing itself.
你会被送回我们的时代
You're being sent back to our proper time.
- 蝙蝠侠 那你呢  - 我没事
- Well, Batman, what about you? - I'll be fine.
去吧 助其他人一臂之力去抵御脑怪
Go, help the others against Brainiac.
我要是你们的话 就会赶紧游泳
If I were you, I'd start swimming.
我那个长了鳍的朋友就在附近 我想他想来打个招呼
My finny friend is nearby and I think he wants to say hello.
游开 游开
Swim away, argh, swim away!
再快点
Faster!
你的样子很糟
Ooh, you don't look so good.
飞鱼偷了我的鸡腿 我需要能量
Flying fish stole my chicken leg, need energy.
这个会有用的
This should help.
你有自己的维他命饮料
You have your own vitamin drink?
犯罪永不干涸 可英雄会
Crime never dries up, but heroes can.
所以我开发了自己的维他命补品
That's why I developed my own vitamin supplement.
喝了它 闪电侠
Drink up, Flash.
我们去救超人
And let's go save Superman.
蝙蝠侠 这玩意太棒了 我从没这么精神过
Batman, this stuff is amazing. I never felt so alive.
还有吗  我还想喝一听 能再来一听吗
Do you have another can? I'd love another can. Can I get another can?
我觉得我能挑战世界
I feel like I can take on the world.
脑怪的无人机就像火牛…
Brainiac's drones fight like the fire oxen of...
电锯 铁锹 食糖 香料
Chainsaw, crowbar, sugar, spice.
干掉他们 不必客套
Smash those robots, don't play nice.
饼干 糖果和炸弹…
Cookies, candies, dynamite...
把脑怪的无人机都炸烂
Brainiac's drones will be destroyed and exploded into a million pieces.
- 我搞定这个 - 嗯 嗯
- I got this. - What? What?
- 你搞定这个 - 谁 谁
- You got this. - Who? Who?
- 我们搞定这个 - 呜呼
- We got this. - Woohoo!
- 耶 - 耶
- Yeah! - Yeah!
年轻人
Ah, youth.
神奇女侠 小心
Wonder Woman, look out.
朋友们 想我没
Hey, gang. Miss me?
哈尔 蝙蝠侠把你也救出来了
Hal, Batman saved you too.
我帮了忙的 可是 他救了我
Well, I helped, but, yeah.
蝙蝠侠
Batman.
所以蝙蝠侠找到了解救神奇女侠和绿灯侠的方法
So, Batman found a way to retrieve Wonder Woman and Green Lantern.
这个混蛋
This stinks.
是你啊
Oh, it's you.
我的船修得怎么样了
How are the repairs to my ship progressing?
幸会啊
It's nice to see you too.
我不是故意无礼的 脑怪1.3 可我正在忙
I didn't mean to be rude, Brainiac 1.3, but I am in the middle of something.
他正在忙
Oh, he's in the middle of something.
也许我们也在忙
Maybe we're in the middle of something too.
你的船修好了83%了
Your ship is 83% complete.
修好了尽快送来
Bring it as soon as it's ready.
可以吗
Oh, can we?
脑怪们
Brainiacs.
让我们看看这些英雄们如何对付来自过去的袭击
Let's see how these heroes deal with a blast from the past.
这是怎么回事
Oh, what now?
也许脑怪传来消息 他要放弃了
Maybe Brainiac is sending a message that he's giving up.
也许他开了个入口 好让其他人回来
Or he's opening a portal in time to return the others.
也许是那个
Or that.
你有没有什么助威词
Do you have a cheer for attacking blood-thirsty dinosaurs
是在打嗜血恐龙的时候说的
that are about to eat us?
不可能
It can't be.
这是未来
The future.
我还以为未来应该都是会飞的车 喷气飞机或者机器人呢
I thought the future would be flying cars or jetpacks or robots.
检测到生命形态 反应初始化
Life forms detected. Initializing response.
击碎
Disintegration.
- 蝙蝠车 出事了 - 稳住 闪电侠
- Batman, something's wrong. - Hold on, Flash.
临时替代能源正在流失
We're losing temporal displacement energy.
时间要把蝙蝠车带回它本该在的地方
Time is snapping the Batmobile to its proper place.
- 蝙蝠侠 - 不用担心我 闪电侠
- Batman! - Don't worry about me, Flash.
去帮其他人
Help the others.
似乎我回不去了
Looks like I lost my ride home.
欢迎来到未来 蝙蝠侠
Welcome to the future, Batman.
超人 谢天谢地我找到你了
Superman, thank goodness I found you.
别谢了 那是错觉
Do not thank goodness, it is an illusion.
谢谢脑怪 他给我升了级 你不喜欢吗
Thank Brainiac. Don't you just love the upgrades he gave me?
不要
No.
没错
Yes.
你们那个时代的脑怪
You see, Brainiac from your era
发现你要穿梭时光要去救我
figured out you were traveling through time to rescue me,
也就是说未来的脑怪也会发现你的计划
which means future Brainiac also became aware of your plans.
所以 他派我来 你一到就干掉你
So, he sent me to destroy you on arrival.
这次时光穿梭太有趣了 不是吗
It's so funny how this time travel stuff works, isn't it?
在你消失前 我们希望你脑怪之城玩得开心
We hope you enjoy your time here in Brainiactropolis before you are vaporized.
别动 就疼一会
Hold still, this will only sting for a brief moment.
执行程序 压碎 删除 消灭蝙蝠侠
Execute programing, crush, delete, destroy Batman.
请记住 这不是私人纠纷
Please remember, it's not personal.
奇怪 动作失灵
That's strange, motion impaired.
是某种磁力区域
Hmm, some kind of magnetic field.
这里还有别人
Someone else is here.
不用会读心术也能搞明白
You don't have to be a mind reader to figure that out.
就是现在 闪电少年
Now, Lightning Lad.
抗不了脑怪超人太久
That won't hold Brainiac-Superman for long.
要是不想变蝙蝠酱 就跟我们走
Come with us if you'd like to avoid being smashed into Bat paste.
- 我不觉得应该信任这些… - "为什么要信任我们
- I don't think I should trust these... - "Why should you trust us?
"我们 我们"
"Us? Us?"
因为 你别无选择
Because, you really don't have any choice.
选择 择
Oice. Oice.
而且 对 我可以读心
And, yeah, I can read minds.
这是土星少女 这是宇宙男孩 就是他创建了磁力区域
Saturn Girl, Cosmic Boy, he is generating that magnetic field,
还有闪电少年…
and Lightning Lad...
有电能 我知道
Electricity power, I got it
我甚至没有心灵感应
and I'm not even a telepath.
他要冲出去了
He's about to break free.
我不是故意抬高自己 可说真的 我是最后被选出来的头儿 所以…
I don't mean to pull rank, but, technically I was the last elected leader, so...
抬高这词真恶心 就像你人一样恶心
Rank is the word, all right, as in your smell.
就算世界终结 肥皂和水也是水火不容的关系
Soap and water are pretty hard to come by since the world ended.
行了 少说几句 快点跑路活命
Okay, less bickering, more escaping with our lives.
欢迎货车的程序被破坏了
My Welcome Wagon program was interrupted.
我必须执行终结蝙蝠侠的程序
I must execute program End Batman.
你们是什么人
Who are you people?
我们以前是超级英雄军团 现在就剩我们几个了
We were the Legion of Super-Heroes, now, we're what's left of them.
把我们当成是反脑怪的反抗军就行
Just think of us as the anti-Brainiac resistance.
脑怪来之前 这地方是乌托邦
Before Brainiac came, this place was a utopia.
也没那么坏 还有很多停车的地方
Hey, it's not all bad. There's plenty of parking spaces.
欢迎来到反抗军总部
Welcome to resistance headquarters.
几个礼拜以后 就会习惯这种下水道的味道了
You'll get used to the sewage smell after a few weeks.
根据历史资料…
According to historical data...
脑怪在你们的时代无法打败超人
Brainiac was unable to defeat Superman in your time,
所以他就把超人丢到了未来 在这 脑怪可以研发技术
so he hurled Superman into a future where Brainiac could develop the technology
同化超人 把他变成终极武器
to assimilate him and turn him into the ultimate weapon.
你能别读我的心吗 能不能有一次容我把话说完
Could you please not read my mind? And stop finishing my sentences for once.
我就没读过你的心 好吗
I never read your mind, okay?
你要说什么一般挺明显的
It's always just obvious what you're going to say next.
历史还告诉我们 你和超人是好朋友
History also tells us that you and Superman were good friends.
你对超人特别的了解 也许我们能用这点来解救他
Maybe we can use your special knowledge of Superman to free him.
然后 我们一起发起革命打倒脑怪
Then, together, we can rise up and defeat Brainiac.
- 耶 - 你觉得呢
- Yeah! - Yeah, what do you say?
我等这一天等了好久了
I've been preparing for this day for a long time.
阻止脑怪超人只有一个方法
There's only one way to stop Brainiac-Superman,
要成功 我得先回哥谭市的蝙蝠洞才行
but to do it, I'll need to get to the Batcave in Gotham City.
你疯了
Are you crazy?
街上都是脑怪的杀人机器人在巡逻
The streets are patrolled by Brainiac's killer robots,
你一出去就会被秒杀
you'd be destroyed the minute you left our hideout.
更别提脑怪超人了
And not to mention Brainiac-Superman.
好主意 蝙蝠侠
Oh, that is a good idea, Batman.
抱歉 他在想韦恩公司有没有
Sorry, he was wondering if Wayne Enterprises
建从大都会到哥谭市的通道
had ever constructed a tunnel from Metropolis to Gotham.
事实上是建了
As a matter of fact, it did.
脑怪的传感器无处不在
Brainiac has sensors everywhere.
你行动以后 他会知道的 还会派出脑怪超人
If you're on the move, he'll know and he'll send Brainiac-Superman.
所以我才希望有人能去拖住他
Then I'll have to hope someone slows him down.
你们看着需要打点气
You guys look like you need a pick-me-up.
再冲点电如何啊
How about a recharge?
击碎
Disintegration.
我不懂你在折腾什么
I don't know why you bother,
你是讨不到好的 他们是杀人机器
you're never going to get a laugh out of them, they're killer robots.
所以我才用杀人材料
That's why I use killer material.
这是一个跆拳道小孩教我的小戏法
That's a little trick Karate Kid taught me.
那能吸引他的注意吗
Think that got his attention?
我觉得是
Oh, I know so.
不是蝙蝠侠 宇宙男孩
不是蝙蝠侠 闪电少年
不是蝙蝠侠 土星女孩
观测 没有蝙蝠侠
Observation, Batman is absent.
真糟 我还期待在干掉他之前
Too bad, I was looking forward to seeing him again...
和他再见一面…
Before I crushed him.
你的对手是我们 还用蝙蝠侠吗
Who needs Batman when you have us?
反抗无效 闪电少年 请勿见怪
Resistance is pointless, Lightning Lad, no offense.
加斯
Garth!
- 洛克 - 蝙蝠侠呢
- Rokk! - Where is Batman?
我要执行欢迎货车的程序
I need to execute my Welcome Wagon program.
远在天边 脑怪超人 你找不到他的
Far from here, Brainiac-Superman, you'll never find him.
话别说太满
Don't be so sure.
祝你今天开心
Have a nice day.
哥谭市 我能闻到
Gotham City. I can smell it.
显而易见 未来的我
Clearly my future self
一定是按照闪电侠的建议 建了大都会到哥谭市的通道
must have followed up on Flash's suggestion of a Metropolis-Gotham tunnel.
闪电侠是对的 厉害
The Flash was right. Amazing.
又回到蝙蝠洞了
The Batcave again.
现在我知道没有阿尔弗雷德收拾蝙蝠洞 千年以后是什么样了
Now I know what 1,000 years without Alfred dusting looks like.
要是地球度过此次难关 我应该给他加薪
If Earth survives, I should give him a raise.
蝙蝠保险柜
The Batsafe.
生锈的门后是拯救地球的关键
Behind its rusted door lies the key to Earth's salvation.
嘿 蝙蝠侠
Oh, hey, Batman.
在这找到你 让我有点失望
Boy, I'm a little disappointed to find you here.
逃到蝙蝠洞是意料之中的事 不是吗
Fleeing to the Batcave, kind of predictable, don't you think?
你还在反抗 蝙蝠侠
You still resist me, Batman?
没人能和脑怪们唱反调
None can stand up to the Brainiac Collective.
来吧 蝙蝠侠
Come on, Batman.
你忘了
Don't you remember?
我最擅长玩捉迷藏了 你逃不过我的法眼
I am the best at hide-and-seek, you cannot hide from me.
是你忘了吧 超人
Don't you remember, Superman?
你从来没跟我玩过捉迷藏
You never played hide-and-seek with me.
另外 谁说我躲了
Besides, who says I'm hiding?
黑暗骑士穿上他的盔甲
So, the Dark Knight dons his armor.
在我的超能力面前不堪一击
It doesn't stand a chance against my Super Strength.
现在我能完成欢迎货车程序了
Now, I can complete the Welcome Wagon program.
为了让你开心 我设定了曲子
For your enjoyment, I have set it to music.
你在未来
So, you're in the future
就不会百无聊赖
And just so you're not bored
来脑怪们中间
Into the Brainiac Collective
你会被吸纳
You will be absorbed
你的战衣和你不搭
Your battle suit won't help you
这仗没什么好打的
This ain't much of a fight
我基本无敌
I'm so darn invulnerable
都不必怕被恐龙咬
Don't even fear a dinosaur bite
现在 一动别动
Now, don't move a muscle
这不会疼
This won't hurt a bit
我要熔掉你的盔甲
I'll melt that armor off you
就在眨眼之间
Lickety-split
谢谢 我就知道那个保险柜锈得很难开
Thank you, I knew that safe would be too rusty to open.
你的旧氪星石
Ah, your old Kryptonite stash.
你说得对 我终究变成了恶魔 现在你要拿它来对付我
Hey, you were right, I finally turned evil and now you get to use it on me.
你未雨绸缪的时候还真是未雨绸缪
Boy, when you plan ahead, you really plan ahead.
氪星石不在今天的计划之内 这个才是
Kryptonite's not part of the plan today, this is.
什么
What is...
聚焦和放大一千倍的黄色太阳光
Yellow sunlight, concentrated and magnified 1,000 times,
足够给超人充电 熔化脑怪
enough to power up Superman and melt down Brainiac.
不 你不可能…
No, you'll never...
干掉他 超人 我知道你还在身体里
Fight him, Superman, I know you're still in there.
超人 克拉克
Superman? Clark?
没有超人了
Superman is no more,
只有脑怪
there is only Brainiac.
你的朋友永远的消失了 蝙蝠侠
Your friend is gone forever, Batman.
朋友
Friends...
蝙蝠侠
Batman...
是我 超人 你能行 你能赢
It's me, Superman, you can do this. You can fight this.
为了地球 为了正义联盟 干掉他
Do it for Earth, do it for the Justice League.
蝙蝠侠 你做到了 你救了我
Batman, you did it, you saved me.
你本可以用氪星石打倒我的
You could've defeated me with your Kryptonite.
可你的太阳光线设备…
But, your sun-ray device...
你是怎么知道这东西能把我从脑怪的影响中唤醒的
How did you know it would wake me from Brainiac's influence?
我不知道 可我得抓住机会
I didn't, but I had to take that chance.
我要时刻准备着解决这世界扔给我的最糟糕的麻烦
It's my job to prepare for the worst that this world can throw at me.
可我也时刻准备着解决朋友的问题
But I also always prepare for a friend in need.
谢谢你 布鲁斯
Thank you, Bruce.
现在 我们去对付脑怪
Now, let's go get Brainiac.
怎么回事
What, what's happening?
现在你要记得 你会被带回你的时代
Now that you remember, you're been drawn back to your own time.
为什么你不会
Why aren't you?
很不幸 我要被困在这了
Unfortunately, I am stranded here.
不
No.
不要让我白白牺牲 超人
Make my sacrifice worthwhile, Superman.
一定要阻止未来变成这个样子
Make sure you stop this future from ever happening.
再见 我的朋友
Goodbye, my friend.
各位 我就知道你们能逃过一劫
Legionnaires, I knew you would find a way to survive.
没错 我们还有别的发现
Yes, and we found something else as well.
好孩子 跟我来
That's a good boy, follow me.
这真是个烂主意
This was a bad idea.
麻烦多多 痛苦多多 恐龙恐龙 此生不见
So much trouble, so much pain, I don't wanna see a dinosaur ever again.
干得漂亮 伙伴们
Nice work, team.
超人
Superman.
- 蝙蝠侠成功了 - 我就知道
- Batman did it! - I knew it.
你干得特别好 超女
Especially good work from you, Supergirl.
成长很快啊 年轻的女士
You're growing up fast, young lady.
等等 蝙蝠侠呢
Wait a minute, where is Batman?
是啊 到底在哪呢
Yes, where indeed?
修复完毕
总算修好了
Ah, finally.
你好 脑怪
Greetings, Brainiac.
脑怪1.2 脑怪1.2 你们迟了0.0761秒
Brainiac 1.2, Brainiac 1.3, you are .0761 seconds late.
我刚把地球上的东西分类完
I just finished cataloging everything on the Earth,
准备开始缩小
I am ready to shrink.
我们要给你个惊喜 脑怪
Well, we have a surprise for you, Brainiac.
缩小光线2.0版本
The Shrink-ray 2.0.
- 你会发现 它特别出众… - 我计算的结果表明
- You will notice, it is even superior to... - My calculations indicate
毫无疑问 这是个诱杀装置
that I will, no doubt, find it is a booby trap
我启动它 就会把我消灭
designed to destroy me when I activate it.
你说得非常对 而且… 等等 什么
You are quite correct and... Wait, what?
显而易见 他的计算能力比咱俩都强
Apparently, his calculations were better than ours.
当然 我是脑怪1.1
Of course, I am Brainiac 1.1.
不管你们如何计算 我都会先算出来
Whatever you calculate, I calculate it first.
是他计算的结果
It was his calculation.
我算出来你会这么说了
I calculated you would say that.
剩下的脑怪按顺序往前挪两个数字
All the other Brainiacs now advance two numbers in rank.
能提升斗志
That should be good for morale.
现在 接着干活
Now, back to work.
诱杀装置失效 外行
Booby trap deactivated, amateurs.
现在我有能力了
Now, I have the power.
肯定有办法回到未来去救蝙蝠侠的 对吗
Well, there's gotta be a way to go back to the future and save Batman, right?
蝙蝠侠要我先从脑怪的手中救出地球
Batman wants us to save the Earth from Brainiac first.
我们之后会找到救出蝙蝠侠的办法的
We'll have to figure out a way to save Batman, later.
不 他不能
Oh, no, he didn't.
我想他做了
I think he did.
任务完成
Ah, mission accomplished.
看天上
Look, up in the sky.
- 好大 - 好可怕
- It's massive. - It's scary.
不 那是…
No, it's... It's...
是个瓶子
It's a bottle.
感谢赫拉
Thank Hera.
- 你回来了 - 蝙蝠侠
- You're back. - Batman.
脑怪赢了 我们被关在瓶子里了
Brainiac has already won, we've been bottled.
可你是怎么回来的
But, how did you get here?
时光球体
Time sphere.
脑怪占领的时候 军团只剩下这一个没被毁的了
The Legion has only one that wasn't destroyed when Brainiac took over.
有足够的力量…
It had just enough power to...
- 可脑怪超人… - 以为他干掉了军团
- But, Brainiac-Superman... - Thought he destroyed the Legion.
可那只是土星女孩投射到你心里的幻觉
But it was all an illusion projected into your mind by Saturn Girl.
现在 让我们拔掉瓶塞 不要被缩小
Now, let's get uncorked and un-shrunk.
就算是结合我们的力量
Even with our combined strength,
还是需要更多的力量才能移开瓶塞
we're gonna need more power to move that big cork.
我想我有个主意
I think I have just the thing.
厉害 钢骨 这些飞机太棒了
Nice work, Cyborg. These jets are swell.
谢谢 等超女拿到她的飞行执照 我再做一架
Thanks, I'll build one more when Supergirl gets her pilot's license.
- 真的  - 等着吧
- Seriously? - We'll see.
好了 各位 我们把火力都集中在一个区域
All right, team, let's all concentrate our firepower in one area.
跟在我后头
Follow my lead.
等等 再等等 发射巨型蝙蝠飞镖
Wait for it, wait for it... Mega batarangs away.
最大限度音速尖叫
Sonic screeches on maximum.
启动热感视力
Heat vision activated.
能源星
Energy stars.
灯激光
Lantern lasers.
加速闪电
Speed force lightning.
很管用
It's working!
塞子掉了 我的一个世界不是原包装的了
Uncorked, one of my world's is no longer in its original packaging.
肯定是正义联盟干的好事
This must be the work of the Justice League.
他们要付出代价
They will pay.
12点钟方向有个妖怪
We got a bogey, 12 o'clock.
中午12点了
It's noon already?
怪不得我饿了
Yeah, no wonder I'm starving.
超女 是脑怪 他在那儿
No, Supergirl, Brainiac, he's right there.
很聪明
Very clever.
一旦我把你们缩小到消失 看你们还怎么聪明
Let us see how clever you are once I shrinkify you into non-existence.
躲避战术
Evasive maneuvers.
粗鲁战术
Abrasive maneuvers.
直面战术
In your face-ive maneuvers.
得找到关闭缩小光线的方法
We've got to figure out a way to turn off his shrink-ray.
我有个主意 可你得去分散他的注意
I have an idea, but it means you have to keep him distracted.
同意 蝙蝠侠
Consider it done, Batman.
好了 各位 都听到蝙蝠侠的话了 上
All right, team, you heard the man, let's do this.
超速旋转攻击
Super-speed spin attack.
气闸 刹住
Air brakes, engage.
脑怪的大脑
Brainiac's brain.
你们地球人让我很头疼
You Earthlings give me such a headache.
迷人
Fascinating.
够了
Enough.
你们愚蠢的声音还有虚构的单词都不能计算
Your silly sounds and imaginary words do not even compute.
我们要输了
We're losing this thing.
我不想打击士气 可是我们要完蛋了
I don't mean to be negative, but we're doomed.
你错了 闪电侠
Wrong, Flash.
我们才刚刚开始
We've only just begun.
钢骨 执行M计划
Cyborg, execute plan M.
是时候使出秘密武器了
It's time for our secret weapon,
正义联盟 初始化联盟机甲
Justice League, initialize Mecha-leaguer.
这个没办法计算
This does not compute.
上吧 联盟机甲
Go, Mecha-leaguer.
好了 脑怪 该跟同等身高的对手打了
Okay, Brainiac, time to pick on someone your own size.
那个 跟你差不多高的对手
Well, almost your own size.
你们要用那可怜的机器人
You would match your pathetic automaton
来抵抗宇宙中最高级的机器人
against the most advanced robot in the universe?
致命的错误…
Fatal error...
多亏我拳头快 成功让他闭嘴
Monolog successfully averted, thanks to my speed fist.
各位 不用客气
You're welcome, everybody.
二 四 六 八 我们乐于恨谁  脑怪 脑怪 脑怪
Two, four, six, eight, who do we love to hate? Brainiac, Brainiac, Brainiac!
快点 钢骨 我们来旋转踢
Come on, Cyborg, let's do our spinning kick.
欧耶
Oh, yeah.
我们上
Let's do this.
形成正义的绿色之锤
Forming Green Sledgehammer of Justice.
投降吧 脑怪
It's time to surrender, Brainiac.
绝不
Never.
我现在要把你们缩小到无
I will now shrink you out of existence.
神奇女侠 上
Wonder Woman, now.
那不是我的缩小光线 是放大光线 怎么会这样
That wasn't my shrink-ray, it was my growth ray, but how?
淡定 脑怪
Easy, Brainiac.
我在你大脑里 重新连接了缩小装置的回路
While I was in your brain, I reconfigured the circuits of your shrink-ray device,
同时 把它的两极颠倒了
simultaneously, reversing its polarity.
所以你没有把我们缩小 反而放大了
So, instead of shrinking us, you grew us.
在你以为你可以用它们之前…
And, before you think you can use either of them again...
我的光线 不
My rays, no.
不
No!
重新计算 重新计算 重新计算
Recalculating, recalculating, recalculating... Ow.
我被打败了
I am defeated.
可随着我收集的程序被阻碍
But with my programing to collect stymied,
飞船到最后只会自爆
this unit has no choice but to self-destruct,
把这附近的一切都炸光
taking everything in this vicinity with it.
十
10...
- 九 - 哦 天哪
- Nine... - Oh, man.
- 八 - 我还以为我们赢了
- Eight... - I thought we just won this thing.
- 等等 脑怪 - 七
- Hold on, Brainiac. - Seven...
- 你说你要做的… - 六
- You say that all you need to do... - Six...
是履行收集的程序
is fulfill your programing to collect?
五 当然
Five... Affirmative.
- 四 - 停止倒数
- Four... - Stop your countdown.
- 我有解决的办法 - 三
- I have a solution. - Three...
暂停
Pause.
1958年印第安人头的一分钱硬币
Ah, a 1958 Indian Head penny.
这是个重新开始收集的好地方
This will be a perfect place to start my new collection.
提问 有人有更多的硬币吗
Query, does anyone have more coins?
我要把它们集全
I must collect them all.
那么 为了稳定控制他的自爆程序 他要收集硬币
So, in order to keep his self-destruct programing at bay, he's collecting coins?
他收集全会怎么样
What happens when he gets them all?
不可能
Impossible.
每年都有新的硬币 他的收集没个头
They mint new coins every year, so his collection can never end.
机灵啊
Ingenious!
蝙蝠侠 我想谢谢你救了我们
Batman, I wanna say thank you for saving us.
我很抱歉说我们只是同事关系
And I'm really sorry for saying that we were merely work friends.
你能把我们从残缺的记忆中救出来
It's obvious by the way you were able to snap us out of our amnesia
是因为你太了解我们了 只有真正的朋友才会那样
that you know a lot about us, as only a true friend would.
谢谢你做我们的朋友
Thank you for being our friend.
不必客气
You're welcome.
现在我有几句话要说
And now I have something to say.
这支队伍急需纪律
This team is in sore need of discipline.
地球的下个威胁已经要找上门了
The next threat to Earth is going to find us prepared.
为什么
Why?
因为接下来我设计的这个新训练叫做…
Because of this new training exercise I devised called...
捉迷藏
Hide-and-seek.
我不抓
Not it.
等等 什么
Wait, what?
你来抓
You're it.
天哪 又是我抓
Oh, man, I'm it, again?
100 99 98 97 96
100, 99, 98, 97, 96,
95… 我从50开始数了啊
95... You know, I'm starting at 50.
50 49…
50, 49...